For this question I'm going to explain how we take an input string,
对于这道题目 我将解释下如何传入输入字符串
which in this case is dot dot dot x dot dot dot dot,
这里是 ···X····
and we change it according to some rules.
并根据某种规则更改该字符串
Now the rules are:
规则如下：
look at three characters in the string
查看字符串中的三个字符
and change the middle one
并根据这里的规则
according to the rules that we have here.
更改中间的字符
Don't worry about the numbers for the moment, I'll come to those later.
暂时不要管这些数字 稍后我会讲解
So for this particular three,
对于这三个字符
we have dot dot x.
分别是··X
Now dot dot x says change the middle element
··X 表示将中间的元素
so that it's an x.
更改为 X
So on the next string, the new string,
对于下个字符串 即新的字符串
that position is going to be an x.
这个位置将是 X
The position before it
该位置之前的位置
dot dot dot
···
well dot dot dot becomes a dot
···变成
in the middle.
中间的一个 ·
Now at the ends
对于两边的字符
we want to link around
我们需要连接起来
so this dot here
对于这里的这个 ·
has to its left a dot
左侧是个 ·
and to its right a dot,
右侧是个 ·
so we have dot dot dot again
还是 ···
and dot dot dot says change the middle
··· 表示将中间字符改成
to a dot.
一个 ·
Now moving along,
继续
the next one we have to fill in is dot x dot.
接着要填充的是 ·X·
Dot x dot says change the middle to an x.
·X· 表示将中间元素改成 X
x dot dot,
X··
change the middle to an x
将中间元素变成 X
dot dot dot again,
还是 ···
middle is a dot
中间是 ·
dot dot dot, middle is a dot
··· 中间是 ·
dot dot and then
··
the first one is the last one here
最后一个是这个第一个点
so dot dot dot again is a dot.
··· 还是 ·
Now that completes one change of the string
字符串第一次更改完毕
and we're going to repeat that again.
我们需要再重复一遍
So, That's the first generation.
这是第一次 generation
This is the second generation.
这是第二次 generation
Now normally when you do this, you'd start at the beginning of the string
通常 我们会从字符串的开头开始操作
but just to explain it, it was easier to show you one in the middle.
但是这里只是为了展示在中间更好操作
So this time we'll do it from the beginning of the string.
这次我们将从字符串的开头开始
So looking at the line above,
看看上面这行内容
we see that the first element in the string
第一个元素的
has a dot to its left,
左侧是个 ·
and a dot to its right, so it's dot dot dot,
右侧是个 · 所以是 ···
so that's a dot.
结果是 ·
Now we have dot dot x,
现在是 ··X
and dot dot x, that's number two here,
··X 是这里的数字 2
gives me an x.
得出 X
dot x x is an x,
·XX 是 X
x x x is a dot.
XXX 是 ·
x x dot, is a dot.
XX· 是 ·
x dot dot is an x.
X·· 是 X
dot dot dot, is a dot.
··· 是 ·
And dot dot dot is also a dot.
··· 还是 ·
And we can continue like that.
继续下去
And so after five generations,
转变五次之后
we have the string dot dot dot x x dot x x.
得出字符串 ···XX·XX
And you see we have quite an interesting pattern building up.
可以看出出现了有趣的规律
Now, we can do this for lots of different
我们可以根据第二行
choices of these dots and x's
用蓝色表示的 · 和 X 选项
in blue, on the second line.
执行很多次操作
In fact, we can do it in 256 different ways.
实际上 可以有 256 个不同的方式
And in order to decide what
为了判断我们将使用哪个 pattern
pattern we're going to use, what rules rather,
即哪个规则
we can give this rule a number.
我们可以为这些规则编个号
Now, wherever I've got an x on the bottom row,
只要底部有个 X
I'm going to add up those numbers,
我就将这些数字相加
so 2 + 4 + 8 + 16,
即 2 + 4 + 8 + 16
and that gives me 30.
结果是 30
So this here uses pattern 30.
所以这里使用的是 pattern 30
Now instead of pattern 30, we could choose a different pattern.
我们可以选择不同的 pattern 而不是 pattern 30
Let's say we choose pattern 69.
假设选择 pattern 69
Now 69, is equal to,
69 等于。。。
now we have to look at these numbers above and
我们需要查看上面的这些数字
work out how to make 69
想想哪些数字相加
out of those numbers.
等于 69
Well, 128 doesn't go into 69, so we don't need any of those.
加上 128 肯定不等于 69 所以不需要这些
64 does so we want a 64.
64 可以 所以写上 64
We don't want any 32's.
不需要 32
We don't want any 16's, nor 8.
不需要 16 也不需要 8
But we do need 4,
但是需要 4
don't need 2, and we do need 1.
不需要 2 但是需要 1
So 64 + 4 + 1, 69.
所以 64 + 4 + 1 等于 69
So that means, that we want 1.
意味着我们需要 1
That means were going to replace dot dot dot,
我们将 ··· 的
the middle element by an x.
中间元素替换为 X
No 2's. We do have a 4.
不需要 2 的确需要 4
We don't have an eight.
不需要 8
We don't have 16.
不需要 16
We don't have 32.
不需要 32
We do have 64,
需要 64
and we don't have 128.
不需要 128
So, we could start off with the same input as before,
可以和之前的输入一样开始
which was, dot dot dot x dot dot dot dot.
即···X····
So when we have a dot at the beginning,
当开头是个 ·
its neighbor on the left is a dot,
左侧是个 ·
and its neighbor on the right is a dot,
右侧是个 ·
we have dot dot dot, and that's replaced with an x.
··· 替换成 X
dot dot dot again, is an x.
还是 ··· 变成 X
dot dot x, is a dot.
··X 变成 ·
Remember, we are looking down here.
注意 我们看的是下面的元素
dot x dot, That's number 4, is an x.
·X· 对应数字 4 是个 X
x dot dot is a dot.
X·· 是个 ·
dot dot dot is an x.
··· 是个 X
and dot dot dot is an x, as well.
··· 还是 X
So that's line 1.
这就是第一行的内容
Continuing with the same thing, I'll fill in a few more lines,
继续下去 再填充几行内容
so that we can see what happens with the pattern.
看看 pattern 会出现什么情况
And now I come to line 6,
现在到了第 6 行
I see that I am getting exactly the same as I had in line 5,
发现这行和第 5 行的完全一样
which means that line 7 will also be exactly the same.
意味着第 7 行也会完全一样
Now, some of the values give you these patterns that just becomes stable,
某些值使这些 pattern 变得稳定起来
others are just chaotic and so there's lots of different things going on
其他值的结果则比较混乱
that can be quite interesting to look at.
所以有很多规律值得研究
Now to come to the actual code.
现在看看实际的代码
What I'm asking you to do is to take as input, a string,
现在请你传入一个字符串
which is a string of dots and x's,
即由 · 和 X 构成的字符串
a pattern number, which is between 0 and 255,
pattern 数字 即 0 到 255 之间的数字
and you're going to have to use that to work out where the dots and x's go.
并据此判断哪些位置是 · 哪些是 X
You will be supplied with this information here,
我会提供这里的这些信息
in other words, the numbers that correspond with the x x dot.
也就是与 XX· 对应的数字
which is the pattern that you look up.
你将研究这一 pattern
And finally, a number of generations, and that's a positive integer.
最后是重复次数 是个正整数
1,2,3,4 and so on.
1 2 3 4 等等
And your output should be the generation,
输出应该是 generation
or the string at that generation n.
或在 generation n 处的字符串
So, for instance, if the input string was, as we have here,
例如 如果输入字符串是这些
the pattern was 69
pattern 是 69
and the generation was five,
generation 是 5
you would return '.x.x.x.x'
则应该返回“.x.x.x.x”